<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">HSSG</string>
    <string name="multiChoice">Multiple Choice Mode</string>
    <string name="scoreButton">View Score</string>
    <string name="fileButton">Select a File</string>
    <string name="preference">Select your preferences</string>
    <string name="submit">Submit</string>
	<string name="tutorial">Welcome Students to the High School Study Guide(HSSG)!\n\nTo get started, select a valid file created by your teacher or use the defaut file when you first begin your quiz. You may change your preferences by pressing the menu button. To create your own study guide visit HSSG Composer at http://bit.ly/14jz3Ne. Once there, download the application and begin to create your own questions, choices, and answers.  Please be sure to have the latest version of Java to run this application.</string>   
    <string name="about">Programmers/Developer: Michael Ang and Derek Li\nDesigner: Jane Rabinovich\nCopyright 2013 Derek Li, Michael Ang\n\nWelcome to the High School Study Guide (HSSG). The HSSG is free software created by Seidenberg Creative Laboratory for non-commercial use.\n\nGithub account: \nhttps://github.com/MichaelAng/HSSG</string>
    <string name="defaultText">Everyday Chemistry@Household Chem@Two household chemicals you should never mix include:@3@ Chloramine vapors can be deadly!@Vinegar and baking soda.@Bleach and water.@Oil and water.@Bleach and ammonia.\nEveryday Chemistry@Sweat@The sweat-blocking ingredient in antiperspirant is often:@0@Try again next time.@An aluminum compound.@A calcium compound.@A magnesium compound.@A tin or stannous compound.\nEveryday Chemistry@Car Batteries@The acid in most car batteries, sometimes known as \'Oil of Vitriol\', is:@3@Try again next time.@Acetic acid.@Hydrochloric acid.@Nitric acid.@Sulfuric acid.\nEveryday Chemistry@Vitamin C@One important source of Vitamin C is citrus fruit. Vitamin C is:@0@Try again next time.@Ascorbic acid.@Citric acid.@Salicylic acid.@Tricarboxylic acid.\nEveryday Chemistry@Soda@Soft drinks may contain many different acids. The acid that produces fizz or bubbles is:@1@Try again next time.@Ascorbic acid.@Carbonic acid.@Citric acid.@Phosphoric acid.\nEveryday Chemistry@Soap@If you are making soaps and detergents from scratch, one of your starting ingredients will be:@1@Try again next time.@Potassium hydroxide.@Sodium hydroxide.@Sodium chloride.@Calcium carbonate.\nEveryday Chemistry@Thimerosol@The chemical known as thimerosol has been used to preserve saline solutions and vaccines. Thimerosol contains which metal?@3@Try again next time.@Iron@Cadmium@Mercury@Silver\nEveryday Chemistry@Preservatives@BHA and BHT are two chemicals commonly used as preservatives in food. What do they preserve?@1@Try again next time.@They keep sugars from degrading.@They are used to keep fats from turning rancid.@They are used to preserve the colors of foods so they remain appetizing.@They prevent artificial sweeteners from decomposing and tasting yucky.\nEveryday Chemistry@Sweeteners@All of these chemicals are sweeteners. Which one is not artificial? (hint: more names doesn\'t mean more natural)@2@Try again next time.@Acesulfame potassium (Ace-K)@Aspartame (Equal, Nutrasweet)@Fructose@Saccharin (Saccharine, Sweet and Low)\nEveryday Chemistry@Chocolate@Chocolate and cocoa naturally contain relatively high levels of which two metals?@0@Try again next time.@Cadmium and lead.@Aluminum and iron.@Cadmium and mercury.@Lead and cobalt.\nAtom Basics@3 Basics@The three basic components of an atom are:@1@Try again next time.@protons, neutrons, and ions@protons, neutrons, and electrons@protons, neutrinos, and ions@protium, deuterium, and tritium\nAtom Basics@Element@An element is determined by the number of:@3@Try again next time.@atoms@electrons@neutrons@protons\nAtom Basics@Nucleus@The nucleus of an atom consists of:@2@Try again next time.@electrons@neutrons@protons and neutrons@protons, neutrons, and electrons\nAtom Basics@Proton@A single proton has what electrical charge?@1@Try again next time.@no charge@positive charge@negative charge@either a positive or negative charge\nAtom Basics@Particle Size and Mass@Which particles have approximately the same size and mass as each other?@2@Try again next time.@neutrons and electrons@electrons and protons@protons and neutrons@none - they are all very different in size and mass\nAtom Basics@Particle Attraction@Which two particles would be attracted to each other?@1@Try again next time.@electrons and neutrons@electrons and protons@protons and neutrons@all particles are attracted to each other\nAtom Basics@Atomic Number@The atomic number of an atom is:@2@Try again next time.@the number of electrons@the number of neutrons@the number of protons@the number of protons plus the number of neutrons\nAtom Basics@Changing neutrons@Changing the number of neutrons of an atom changes its:@0@Try again next time.@isotope@element@ion@charge\nAtom Basics@Changing electrons@When you change the number of electrons on an atom, you produce a different:@1@Try again next time.@isotope@ion@element@atomic mass\nAtom Basics@Electrons@According to atomic theory, electrons are usually found@2@Try again next time.@in the atomic nucleus@outside the nucleus, yet very near it because they are attracted to the protons@outside the nucleus and often far from it - most of an atom\'s volume is its electron cloud@either in the nucleus or around it - electrons are readily found anywhere in an atom\nElement Number@Hydrogen@Hydrogen is the most abundant element in the universe. The atomic number of hydrogen is:@0@Try again next time.@1@2@3@4\nElement Number@Carbon@An important element is carbon, which is found in all organic molecules. How many protons are in an atom of carbon?@1@Try again next time.@4@6@12@16\nElement Number@Oxygen@You need oxygen to breathe. Pure oxygen is most commonly found as a molecule, O2, or sometimes as ozone, O3. What is the atomic number of oxygen?@1@Try again next time.@6@8@9@12\nElement Number@Helium@The second most abundant element in the universe is helium. Do you know how many protons it has?@1@Try again next time.@1@2@3@4\nElement Number@Iron@Iron has been known since prehistoric time. This metal is found in hemoglobin, many magnets, and steel. What is its atomic number?@2@Try again next time.@4@14@26@28\nElement Number@Nitrogen@About 70% of air is nitrogen. Ionized nitrogen is responsible for the orange-red, blue-green, blue-violet, and deep violet colors of the aurora. Do you know its atomic number?@1@Try again next time.@6@7@8@9\nElement Number@Boron@Boron is a semi-metal or metalloid, which has characteristics of metals and nonmetals. Elemental boron conducts infrared light. Boron is found in borosilicate glass, borax, electrical insulators, and lubricants. What is its atomic number?@1@Try again next time.@4@5@13@14\nElement Number@Scandium@Do you know the atomic number of scandium? You may be unfamiliar with this element, but it is the first transition metal found on the periodic table. The blue color of the gemstone aquamarine is due to the presence of scandium.@1@Try again next time.@20@21@30@31\nElement Number@Fluorine@Fluorine is the first halogen found in the periodic table. Pure fluorine is a corrosive yellow gas, with a characteristic odor. Do you know its atomic number?@2@Try again next time.@7@8@9@10\nElement Number@Lithium@Do you know how many protons are in an atom of lithium? This is the lightest of the metals, with the highest specific heat of any solid element.@2@Try again next time.@1@2@3@4\nUnits of Measurement@Newton@The newton is a unit of:@1@Try again next time.@mass@force@pressure@energy\nUnits of Measurement@Mass@Which of the following is not a unit of mass?@2@Try again next time.@gram@mole@pint@ton\nUnits of Measurement@Square Meter@A square meter is a unit of:@2@Try again next time.@volume@length@area@energy\nUnits of Measurement@Volume@Which of these is a unit of volume?@3@Try again next time.@ergs@nanometers@milligrams@cubic centimeters\nUnits of Measurement@Kilometer@The kilometer is a unit of:@1@Try again next time.@mass@length@force@frequency\nUnits of Measurement@Electrical Resistance@A unit of electric resistance is the:@0@Try again next time.@ohm@weber@tesla@henry\nUnits of Measurement@Pascal@The pascal is a unit of:@3@Try again next time.@power@energy@force@pressure\nUnits of Measurement@Temperature@Which of the following is not a unit of temperature?@1@Try again next time.@Kelvin@British thermal unit or BTU@degrees Celsius@degrees Fahrenheit\nUnits of Measurement@Watts@The watt is a unit of?@1@Try again next time.@force@power@electric current@electric charge\nUnits of Measurement@Luminous Intensity@Which of the following is a unit of luminous intensity?@1@Try again next time.@lux@candela@lumen@farad\nAcids and Bases@Acid and Base@Which of the following statements is true concerning acids and bases?@1@Try again next time.@acids and bases don\'t react with each other@acids mixed with bases neutralize each other@acids mixed with bases make stronger bases@acids mixed with bases make stronger acids\nAcids and Bases@Bases@Bases are sometimes called:@0@Try again next time.@Alkalis@Alcohol@Acids@Platforms\nAcids and Bases@Acid Properties@Which is the correct set of acid properties, as described by Boyle:@1@Try again next time.@sour taste, corrosive, change litmus from red to blue@sour taste, corrosive, change litmus from blue to red@sweet taste, slippery, change litmus from blue to red@sour taste, slippery, change litmus from blue to red\nAcids and Bases@Neutral Solutions@Neutral solutions have a pH of:@1@Try again next time.@0@7@9@14\nAcids and Bases@Amphoteric Substance@An amphoteric substance can act as:@3@Try again next time.@Neutralizer@Acid@Base@Both an acid and a base\nAcids and Bases@Dissociate in Water@Which substance completely dissociates in water?@1@Try again next time.@weak acids@strong acids@weak bases@strong bases\nAcids and Bases@Chemical Species@A chemical species having one ionizable hydrogen ion is:@0@Try again next time.@monoprotic@diprotic@triprotic@polyprotic\nAcids and Bases@Vinegar and Juice@Vinegar, fruit juice, and cola are examples of:@1@Try again next time.@strong acids@weak acids@strong bases@weak bases</string>
</resources>